Guide to the Washington State Association of the U.A. Plumbers and Pipefitters Records
Special Collections, University of Washington Libraries
Washington State Association of the U.A. Plumbers and Pipefitters records
1941-2006
1955-1980
University of Washington Libraries Special Collections Box 352900 Seattle, WA 98195-2900
5800
5800-001
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry.$bWashington State Association
6.06 cubic feet 6 boxes
1 oversize folder
Records of the Washington State Association of the U.A. Plumbers and Pipefitters
Washington State Association of U.A Plumbers and Pipefitters (WSA) was founded in 1921 to promote cooperation of all plumber and pipefitters local unions in the State of Washington so they may protect each local union member from "unjust and injurious competition."
In 1995, the WSA established an organizing department funded by all working members of the WSA to address lost market share and union density, and is one of the earliest statewide organizing systems in the United States. The WSA coordinates and funds organizing activities in area U.A. Plumbers & Pipefitters locals and works to prevent the open shop. The WSA has signed nearly 200 contractors since it started and has organized over 1,000 new members. The WSA is active legislatively and politically, coordinating political action of local unions and their members at both the local and national level.
As of 2013, the WSA had 7,324 members belonging to six local unions, all of which are United Association affiliates. The association's affilates are: UA Local 26- Western Washington Plumbers and Steamfitters; UA Local 32- Seattle Plumbers and Steamfitters; UA Local 44- Spokane Plumbers and Steamfitters; UA Local 598- Pasco Plumbers and Steamfitters; UA Local 669- Road Sprinklerfitters; UA Local 699- Seattle Sprinklerfitters
This collection documents the numerous activities of the Washington State Association of U.A. Plumbers and Pipefitters (WSA) and the interactions with its various locals throughout the state of Washington: Local 32 (Seattle), Local 40 (Bellingham), Local 44 (Spokane), Local 82 (Tacoma), Local 175 (Mount Vernon), Local 358 (Aberdeen), Local 549 (Yakima), Local 598 (Kennewick/Pasco), Local 631 (Bremerton) and Local 695 (Longview). The collection spans from 1945-2006. The bulk of the documents from this collection originated from the internal departments of the WSA; some materials were collected from various offshoots of the WSA. The largest series in the collection is WSA Conventions and Resolutions (Series XII), which details the substantial planning and execution of forty-two separate annual conventions from 1946-1992, including the 50th “Golden Anniversary” Convention held in Yakima in 1971. Also of note are the numerous legal cases found in Legal Files (Series IX). There are particularly extensive materials on two National Labor Relations Board Cases: the Harless Case (Local 598 [Pasco] and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators) and the MacDonald and Scott Associates Case (Plumbers and Steamfitters Locals 598 (Kennewick) and 44 (Spokane) and McDonald-Scott & Associates. Projects and disputes pertaining specifically to union authority can be found in Jurisdictional Documents (Series X). The materials located in Executive Board (Series I) and Washington State Board of Negotiators (Series II) highlight the issues most pertinent to the WSA, as well as the ways in which the issues were resolved. Mergers (Series VII) shows the ways in which the locals were consolidated or absorbed into larger locals throughout the years. Although Board of Trustees (Series III), Business Managers (Series IV), Pension Committee (Series V) and Residential Housing (Series VI) are all smaller series, they offer insight into the disparate subjects that various groups within the WSA have dealt with in the past. The day-to-day workings of the WSA can be evaluated from the Financial Documents (Series VIII) and Office Files (Series XI). WSA Locals (Series XIII) gives a glimpse into the issues most relevent to individual locals of the WSA.
The accession is arranged into 13 series.
Series I: Executive Board, 1950-1993
Series II: Washington State Board of Negotiators, 1958-1981
Series III: Board of Trustees, 1956, 1971
Series IV: Business Managers, 1973
Series V: Pension Committee, 1961-1962
Series VI: Residential Housing, 1971-1981; 2006
Series VII: Mergers, 1972-1988
Series VIII: Financial Documents, 1962-2000
Series IX: Legal Files, 1954-1975
Series X: Jurisdictional Documents, 1945-1983; 1996-1997
Series XI: Office Files, 1951-1992
Series XII: WSA Conventions and Resolutions, 1941-1992
Series XIII: WSA Locals, 1955-1972
Each series is arranged by material format. Within these sub-series, individual files are arranged in either chronological or reverse chronological order, depending on the original order in which the items were found.
View selections from this collection in digital format
Records are stored offsite; advance notice required for use.
Open to all users
Donor: Randy Scott, Executive Secretary-Treasurer, 2013.
The visual materials that form part of this collection are described and indexed in the guide to the
.
United Association of Journeymen and Apprentices of the Plumbing and Pipe Fitting Industry.$bWashington State Association$vArchives;; Labor Archives of Washington (University of Washington)
Personal Papers/Corporate Records;; Labor Unions; Washington (State)
- SERIES I: EXECUTIVE BOARD, 1950-1993 (Box-folder 1/1-1/16; 2/10)
  Series I includes extensive meeting minutes for the WSA Executive Board from 1950-1993, as well as a small amount of the Executive Board’s correspondence from the 1960s. There is also a few undated lists of Executive Board Members.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Executive Board: Meeting Minutes; Subseries B: Executive Board: Correspondence; Subseries C: Officers and Executive Board Members Lists, pre-1980.
  - Subseries A: Executive Board: Meeting Minutes, 1950-1993 (Box-folder 1/1-1/14)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 1/1)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 1/2)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 1/3)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 1/3, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1/4)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 2/3, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1/5)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 3/3, 1970-1980 (Box-folder 1/6)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 1/2, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1/7)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 2/2, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 1/8)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 1/3, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 1/9)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 2/3, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 1/10)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 3/3, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 1/11)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 1/3, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 1/12)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 2/3, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 1/13)
    - Executive Board Meeting Minutes, Part 3/3, 1950-1963 (Box-folder 1/14)
  - Subseries B: Executive Board: Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 1/16; 2/10)
    - Correspondence re: 7 Point Trust Supplement Revisions Proposed by Local 32, 1967 (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Correspondence re: Referendum Voting, 1965 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Subseries C: Officers and Executive Board Members Lists, pre-1980, Undated (Box-folder 1/15)
- SERIES II: WASHINGTON STATE BOARD OF NEGOTIATORS, 1958-1981, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 1/18-1/21; 1/23-1/25; 2/1-2/5)
  Series II includes meeting minutes and correspondence, as well as a handful of contract negotiations. The series also includes a 1954 committee resolution and the minutes from the trial of Board of Negotiators member Grant Wood.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Meeting Minutes; Subseries B: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Correspondence; Subseries C: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Resolution; Subseries D: Minutes of the Grant Wood Trial.
  - Subseries A: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Meeting Minutes, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 1/23-1/25)
    - Board of Negotiators Meeting Minutes, Part 1/3, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 1/23)
    - Board of Negotiators Meeting Minutes, Part 2/3, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 1/24)
    - Board of Negotiators Meeting Minutes, Part 3/3, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 1/25)
  - Subseries B: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Correspondence, 1958-1981, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 1/18-1/19)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Correspondence & Voting re: 1961 Strike (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Subseries C: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Contract Negotiations, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 2/1-2/5)
    - Contract Negotiations, 1962 (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Contract Negotiations, 1961 (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Contract Negotiations, Part 1/2, 1960 (Box-folder 2/3)
    - Contract Negotiations, Part 2/2, 1960 (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Contract Negotiations, 1959 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Subseries D: Washington State Board of Negotiators: Resolution, 1954 (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Subseries E: Minutes of Grant Wood Trial, 1964 (Box-folder 1/21)
- SERIES III: BOARD OF TRUSTEES, 1956; 1971 (Box-folder 1/22)
  Series III includes a few sets of meeting minutes from the Board of Trustees.
  - Board of Trustees: Meeting Minutes, 1956; 1971 (Box-folder 1/22)
- SERIES IV: BUSINESS MANAGERS, 1973 (Box-folder 1/17)
  Series IV includes the minutes from a 1973 meeting of the Tri-State Business Managers.
  - Business Manager Tri-State Meeting Minutes, 1973 (Box-folder 1/17)
- SERIES V: PENSION COMMITTEE, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/1-3/4)
  Series V includes the Pension Committee’s meeting minutes and expenses from 1961-1962. There is also a Pension Plan and Agreement and Declaration of Trust from 1962.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Pension Committee: Meeting Minutes; Pension Committee: Meeting Expenses; Subseries C: Pension Plan and Agreement and Declaration of Trust.
  - Subseries A: Pension Committee: Meeting Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/1-3/2)
    - Pension Committee Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, Part 1/2, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Pension Committee Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, Part 2/2, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/2)
  - Subseries B: Pension Committee Meeting Expenses, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 3/3)
  - Subseries C: Pension Plan and Agreement and Declaration of Trust, 1962 (Box-folder 3/4)
- SERIES VI: RESIDENTIAL HOUSING, 1971-1981; 2006 (Box-folder 5/1-5/7)
  Series VI includes minutes, correspondence and contract negotiations of the Residential Housing committee. The bulk of the materials are from the 1970s.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Residential Housing: Meeting Minutes; Subseries B: Residential Housing: Correspondence; Subseries C: Residential Housing: Contract Negotiations.
  - Subseries A: Residential Housing: Meeting Minutes, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 5/4)
  - Subseries B: Residential Housing: Correspondence, 1971; 1981; 2006 (Box-folder 5/2; 5/6-5/7)
    - National Residential Memo from UA to WSA Business Managers, 2006 (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Residential Housing Correspondence, 1971 (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Residential Housing Correspondence, 1981 (Box-folder 5/7)
  - Subseries C: Residential Housing: Contract Negotiations, 1975-1981, 1974-1981 (Box-folder 5/1; 5/3; 5/5)
    - Residential Housing Agreements, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Newspaper Article Reporting on New Residential Housing Agreement, 1977 (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Housing Negotiations '81, 1981 (Box-folder 5/5)
- SERIES VII: MERGERS, 1972-1988 (Box-folder 2/6-2/9; 2/13-12/14)
  Series VII includes materials relating to various mergers between different locals in the WSA during the 1970s and 1980s.
  The files in this series are arranged chronologically.
  - Local 358 (Aberdeen) Consolidated into Local 82 (Tacoma), 1972 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Local 549 (Yakima) Merged into Local 598, 1973 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Local 669 (Road Sprinkler Fitters) Accepted into the Washington State Association, 1975 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Memorandum of Understanding: Formation of the Northwest States Pipe Trades Association, 1984 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Local 265 Consolidation into Local 32 and Member Opposition, Part 1/2, 1988 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Local 265 Consolidation into Local 32 and Member Opposition, Part 2/2, 1988 (Box-folder 2/14)
- SERIES VIII: FINANCIAL DOCUMENTS, 1962-2000 (Box-folder 2/18-2/28)
  Series VIII includes complete financial audits of the WSA for the years 1962-1980, as well as two other financial ledgers, one which covers the years 1982-2000.
  The series is subdivided by material format: Subseries A: Audit Reports; Subseries B: Per Capita Payments; Subseries C: General Financial Journal with Closing Materials. The materials in Subseries A: Audit Reports are arranged in reverse chronological order.
  - Subseries A: Audit Reports, 1962-1980 (Box-folder 2/18-2/26)
    - Audit Reports, 1977-1980 (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Audit Reports, Part 1/2, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Audit Reports, Part 2/2, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Audit Reports, Part 1/2, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Audit Reports, Part 2/2, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Audit Reports, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Audit Reports, Part 1/2, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Audit Reports, Part 2/2, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Audit Reports, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Subseries B: Per Capita Payments, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Subseries C: General Financial Journal with Closing Entries, 1982-2000 (Box-folder 2/28)
- SERIES IX: LEGAL FILES, 1954-1975 (Box-folder 2/16; 3/5-3/27; 4/1-4/10; 4/12-4/21; 4/23-4/27)
  Series IX includes a large number of legal cases from 1954-1975, the bulk of which are from the late 1950s and early 1960s. Cases deal with disputes over union membership, breaches of contract, hiring procedures and discrimination in the workplace.
  The series is subdivided first by the legal arena in which the cases were settled: Subseries A: National Labor Relations Board Cases; Subseries B: County Court Cases; Subseries C: United States District Court for the Western State of Washington; Subseries D: United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit; Subseries E: Miscellaneous Legal Files. Subseries A: National Labor Relations Board Cases is further subdivided by which WSA local was involved in the case and arranged numerically: Part 1: Local 32 (Seattle); Part 2: Local 40 (Bellingham); Part 3: Local 82 (Tacoma); Part 4: Local 549 (Yakima); Part 5: Local 598 (Kennewick); Part 6: Local 695 (Longview); Part 7: Cases Involving Multiple Locals. Within each part, individual files are arranged chronologically. Subseries B: County Court Cases is further subdivided by county court location and arranged alphabetically: Part 1: Franklin County Court; Part 2: King County Court; Part 3: Pierce County Court; Part 4: Skagit County Court; Part 5: Snohomish County Court. Within each part, individual files are arranged chronologically. Individual files in Subseries C: United States District Court for the Western State of Washington and Subseries E: Miscellaneous Legal Files are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries A: National Labor Relations Board Cases, 1955-1973 (Box-folder 2/16; 3/8-3/17; 3/22-3/25; 4/7-4/9; 4/12-4/19; 4/21; 4/23; 4/25)
    - Part 1: Local 32 (Seattle), 1958-1964 (Box-folder 3/22-3/23; 4/8)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Union Local 32 (Seattle) - Svensson, et. al. NLRB 19-CB-628, 1959 (Box-folder 3/22)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Union Local 32 (Seattle) - Nelson NLRB 19-CB-649, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3/23)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Local 32 (Seattle) and Walter J. Davy - NLRB Case No. 19-CB-943, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Part 2: Local 40 (Bellingham), 1963 (Box-folder 4/7)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Local 40 (Bellingham) and Frederick Kendell - NLRB Case No. 19-CB-972, 1963 (Box-folder 4/7)
    - Part 3: Local 82 (Tacoma), 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4/11)
      - Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 82 (Tacoma) and Alaskan Copper Company - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-198, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Part 4: Local 549 (Yakima), 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/24)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Local 549 (Yakima) - NLRB 19-CB-418 and 19-CA-1335, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/24)
    - Part 5: Local 598 (Kennewick/Pasco), 1961-1962, 1955-1962 (Box-folder 3/8-3/17; 4/12-4/13)
      - Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 598 (Kennewick) and Weakley and Ziemba - NLRB Cases 19-CB-799-1 and 19-CB-799-2, 1961 (Box-folder 4/12)
      - Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 598 (Kennewick) and Pittsburgh Testing Laboratories - NLRB Case No. 19-CA-2541, 1962 (Box-folder 4/13)
      - Harless Case, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/8-3/17)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 1/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/8)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 2/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/9)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 3/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/10)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 4/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/11)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 5/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/12)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 6/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/13)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 7/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/14)
        - Local 598 (Pasco) and Harless, et. al. and Washington State Board of Negotiators - National Labor Relations Board, Part 8/8, 1955-1958 (Box-folder 3/15)
        - Harless Case Correspondence, Part 1/2, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 3/16)
        - Harless Case Correspondence, Part 2/2, 1956-1958 (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Part 6: Local 695 (Longview), 1956-1960, 1957-1960 (Box-folder 3/25; 4/25)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Local 695 (Longview) - Pacific Natural Gas Company NLRB 19-RC-2076, 1957-1958 (Box-folder 3/25)
      - Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 695 (Longview) and Copper Plumbing & Heating Co. - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-153, 1960 (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Part 7: Cases Involving Multiple Locals, 1956-1973 (Box-folder 2/16; 4/9; 4/14-4/19; 4/21; 4/23)
      - NLRB Compliance Documents, 1956-1967 (Box-folder 4/21)
      - McDonald-Scott & Associates Case, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4/14-4/19)
        - Plumbers and Steamfitters Locals 598 (Kennewick) and 44 (Spokane) and McDonald-Scott & Associates - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-136, Part 1/5, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4/14)
        - Plumbers and Steamfitters Locals 598 (Kennewick) and 44 (Spokane) and McDonald-Scott & Associates - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-136, Part 2/5, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4/15)
        - Plumbers and Steamfitters Locals 598 (Kennewick) and 44 (Spokane) and McDonald-Scott & Associates - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-136, Part 3/5, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4/16)
        - Plumbers and Steamfitters Locals 598 (Kennewick) and 44 (Spokane) and McDonald-Scott & Associates - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-136, Part 4/5, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4/17)
        - Plumbers and Steamfitters Locals 598 (Kennewick) and 44 (Spokane) and McDonald-Scott & Associates - NLRB Case No. 19-CC-136, Part 5/5, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 4/18)
        - McDonald-Scott & Associates Meeting of May 9, 1960 (Box-folder 4/19)
      - UA Local 32 (Seattle) and UA Local 367 (Anchorage) - NLRB Case No. 19-CB-856, 1962 (Box-folder 4/23)
      - UA Locals 32 (Seattle), 40 (Bellingham), 82 (Tacoma), 175 (Mount Vernon), 358 (Aberdeen), 549 (Yakima), 598 (Pasco), 631 (Bremerton) and 695 (Longview) and Cascade Natural Gas Company - NLRB Case No. 19-CD-85, 1964 (Box-folder 4/9)
      - Local 598 Withdrawal from Multi-Employer--Multi-Union Bargaining and NLRB Petitions, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Subseries B: County Court Cases, 1955-1964 (Box-folder 3/5; 3/7; 3/26-3/27; 4/1-4/3; 4/5-4/6; 4/20; 4/22)
    - Part 1: Franklin County Court, 1955-1959 (Box-folder 3/7; 3/26)
      - Harless vs. Local 598 (Kennewick) - Franklin County Court, 1955 (Box-folder 3/7)
      - Plumbers & Steamfitters Local 598 (Kennewick) - In the Matter of Cape and Phillip - Franklin County Court Case No. 9456, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Part 2: King County Court, 1964, 1964-1964 (Box-folder 3/5; 4/5)
      - Local 32 (Seattle) and Local 175 (Mount Vernon) vs. Board of Negotiators and WSA - King County Court Case No. 632075, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 3/5)
      - UA Local 32 (Seattle) vs. Board of Negotiators/Executive Board of the UA/WSA - King County Court - Multiple Cases, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Part 3: Pierce County Court, 1962, 1961-1962 (Box-folder 4/22)
      - Roy vs. Lasham and UA Local 82 (Tacoma) - Pierce County Court Case No. 149561, 1962 (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Part 4: Skagit County Court, 1964 (Box-folder 4/6)
      - PM Northwest, Inc. vs. UA Local 175 (Mount Vernon) - Skagit County Court Case No. 26620, 1964 (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Part 5: Snohomish County Court, 1956-1960 (Box-folder 3/27; 4/1-4/3; 4/20)
      - Klones Case, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 4/1-4/3; 4/20)
        - Klones vs. UA Local 265 (Everett) - Snohomish County Court Case No. 65851, Part 1/3, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 4/1)
        - Klones vs. UA Local 265 (Everett) - Snohomish County Court Case No. 65851, Part 2/3, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 4/2)
        - Klones vs. UA Local 265 (Everett) - Snohomish County Court Case No. 65851, Part 3/3, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 4/3)
        - Klones Appeal - State of Washington Employment Security Department, 1958-1960 (Box-folder 4/20)
      - Salamonsen vs. UA Local 265 (Everett) - Snohomish County Court Case No. 66319, 1959 (Box-folder 3/27)
  - Subseries C: United States District Court for the Western District of Washington, 1957-1964, 1956-1964 (Box-folder 3/20; 4/10)
    - Graham vs. UA Local 32 et. al. - District Court for the Western District of Washington, Northern Division - Case No. 6164, 1964 (Box-folder 4/10)
    - M-3: Hoffman Engineering Corp. v. UA Local 695 District Court for the United States for the Western District of Washington, Southern Division - No 2103, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 3/20)
  - Subseries D: United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit, 1970 (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Civil Rights Suit - United States vs. UA Local 32 (Seattle), et. al. - United States Court of Appeals for the Ninth Circuit Case No. 26048, 1970 (Box-folder 4/27)
  - Subseries E: Miscellaneous Legal Files, 1954-1975 (Box-folder 3/6; 3/18-3/19; 3/21; 4/4; 4/24; 4/26)
    - Miscellaneous 1950s Legal Cases, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Plumbers & Steamfitters Union Local 175 (Mount Vernon) Legal Cases, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 3/21)
    - James J. Molthan 9/1/59 Retainer, 1959 (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Plumbers and Steamfitters Local 549 (Yakima) and Whitechester Heating Co., Inc., 1960 (Box-folder 4/26)
    - James J. Molthan Legal Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 4/4)
    - Vacation Account - L. L. Webster, 1961 (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Civil Action Suit - PMC vs. PPC of the NW, Local 32 (Seattle), Local 598 and Miscellaneous Employers, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 3/6)
- SERIES X: JURISDICTIONAL DOCUMENTS, 1945-1983; 1996-1997, 1941-1983; 1996-1997 (Box-folder 2/15; 5/9-5/29)